start with a 4x2 rectangle
and subdivide both sides
half of the width of the rectangle has
length two
we can swing a matching length around
until it intersects the line cutting
through the middle of the rectangle like
this
and we use that line
to create an equilateral triangle
sitting inside the left half of the
rectangle
because the triangle is equilateral and
has side length 2
the horizontal altitude of the triangle
must be the square root of 3.
[Music]
connect the two edges labeled 2
and we create an isosceles triangle as
the two side lengths are equal
the interior obtuse angle is formed from
a 90 degree angle and a 60 degree angle
so it measures 150 degrees
consequently the other two angles in the
isoscele triangle must be equal and so
are 15 degrees and therefore the
complementary angle here is 75 degrees
using a similar argument we can create
another isosceles triangle seen here
one angle is supplementary to 150
degrees so it's 30 degrees this means
the other two angles which are equal
must both be 75 degrees
now we focus only on the lower half of
the rectangle with side lengths of one
using this highlighted right triangle we
determined that the tangent of 75
degrees is the opposite side length over
the adjacent side length of one so the
tangent of 75 is two plus root three
we can use this other highlighted
triangle with angle 15 degrees because
it's complementary to 75 to see that the
tangent of 15 is 2 minus root 3 all
divided by 1.
we have used a rectangle and not the
half angle identity for tangent to
determine that the tangent of 75 is 2
plus root 3 and the tangent of 15 is 2
minus root 3.
[Music]
you